Guide to the Miguel Gandert Photographs, ca. 1975-1998
Department of Special Collections
Gandert, Miguel. Photographs,
ca. 1975-1998
M1016
Gandert, Miguel.
7 linear ft. (229 photographs and .75 feet printed material)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The collection contains 229 photographs documenting His work deals with Hispanic rituals, family life, and gang life. In addition to the photographic prints there are related books, magazines, reviews, and clippings.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 1998.
Biography
Miguel Gandert has been making powerful images of various aspects of contemporary Hispanic culture in New Mexico for over 20 years. His work deals with Hispanic rituals, family life, and gang life in a manner that is denied to most other photographers. His work qualifies as both art and documentary. He is currently teaching at the University of New Mexico.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
In addition to the photographic prints there are related books, magazines, reviews, and clippings.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Hispanic American art.; Hispanic Americans.; Photography--Albuquerque (N.M.); Photoprints.; Photographers.
Collection Contents
- 9 Tamarind artists proofs from the "Reflexiones del Corazon," portfolio 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 21 matted prints from the series, "Colonias de Nogales, Mexico" 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 26 matted prints from the series "La Frontera: a Way to Survive" 1987-1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- 4 boxers from the series, "Two Corners of a Ring"1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- 2 wrestlers from the series, "Two Corners of a Ring"1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- 5 prints from Ecuador1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- 2 portraits of judgesnd (Box 3, Folder 4)
- 2 color prints from Albuquerque's Hispano barrios1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- 3 color prints from the New Mexico State Fair1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- 6 miscellaneous New Mexico color images1979-1989, nd (Box 4, Folder 3)
- 4 prints from the series, "Being with it: Images from the New Mexico State Fair"1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- 2 prints from the series, "Let's Boogie at Okies"1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- 1 print of Miguel Gandert photographing Oscar Monroy in Nogalesnd (Box 4, Folder 6)
- 23 prints from the series, "Los Comanches de Talpa1994-1998 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- 9 prints, "Tierra Amarilla" (Tierra O Muerte)1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- 9 prints from the series, "Hispano farms in the Rio Arriba Bioregion"1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- 9 prints from the series, "Los Peregrinos de Tome"1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- 20 prints from the series, "VSJ/Scenes from an Urban Chicano Experience"1983-1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- 2 prints from the series, "Martineztown, Santa Barbara"1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- 7 Indo-Hispano portraits1995-1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- 16 New Mexico portraits1976-1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- 2 New Mexico landscapes1989 & 1993 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- 23 miscellaneous prints1984-1997 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- 3 prints of San Luis1995-1997 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- 3 sheets contact printsnd (Box 7, Folder 1)
- 1 print of Apple vendor, Las Vegas1979 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Poster nd (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Interview with Gandert in THE, Santa Fe's monthly magazine of the arts1998 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- News clippings1985-1997 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Flyers for exhibits1988-1997 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Flyers for exhibits1988-1998 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Articlesnd (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Exhibit catalog1994 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Calendar1995 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Spanish Market; magazine of the Spanish Colonial Arts Society1998 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Phoenix Art Museum. "Contemporary Identities"1993 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- "Tome pilgrimage," in New Mexico1994 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Exhibit catalog1993 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Design Book Review1986 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Nuestras Mujeres1992 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- New Mexico, celebrating 400 years of history1998 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- People, en espanol1998 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- New Mexico, Hispanic Arts issue1988 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- "Mystery of the Matachines," in Santa Fean, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- "Not for Sale," in Quantum1996 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- "Gallery, Riding Low," in American Photographer, p. 361984 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Albuquerque Living1984 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- "Portraits without people," in Mirage1993 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- "From the heart, of the heart," in Mirage1994 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Mirage1997 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Sin Fronteras, crossing borders1989 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Chispas!, cultural warriors of New Mexico1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Reflexiones del Corazon1996 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- "La Querencia: Moctezuma and the landscape of desire," in Blue Mesa Review, #71995 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- "Creating destruction - the fiftieth anniversary of the Trinity site," in Blue Mesa Review, #8[1996?] (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Luna Cornea, # 71995 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Whitney Museum of American Art. 1993 Biennial Exhibition1993 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Miguel Gandert: Photographer / produced by Sandy Garritano for KNME TV5 Albuquerque, New Mexico, 11/5/86 & 11/8/861986, 1 videotape; 3/4 in. U-Matic (Box 9, Folder 5)
  Requires two weeks advance notice in order to arrange for use copy to be made.